<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20260115</CreaDate><CreaTime>16183200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce></Esri><toolbox name="yaml_toolbox" alias="yamlanalysistoolbox"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><toolsets /></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>YAML Analysis Toolbox</resTitle></idCitation><idPurp>A proof-of-concept ArcGIS Pro Python Toolbox demonstrating configuration-driven 
tool development using YAML files. Eliminates boilerplate code through dynamic 
tool generation.</idPurp><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This toolbox provides a modern approach to ArcGIS Pro Python Toolbox development&lt;BR/&gt;by using YAML configuration files to define tools instead of writing repetitive&lt;BR/&gt;wrapper classes. Tools are dynamically generated at runtime, allowing developers&lt;BR/&gt;to focus on business logic while the framework handles parameter management,&lt;BR/&gt;validation, and ArcGIS Pro integration.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Features:&lt;BR/&gt;- Zero boilerplate - Define tools in YAML, write only business logic&lt;BR/&gt;- Automatic parameter management with type validation&lt;BR/&gt;- Runtime validation rules defined in configuration&lt;BR/&gt;- Comprehensive metadata documentation support&lt;BR/&gt;- Self-documenting through YAML configuration&lt;BR/&gt;- Easy to test with mocked arcpy&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>Developed as a proof of concept for YAML-based ArcGIS Pro Python Toolbox 
development. Demonstrates modern software engineering practices including 
configuration-driven development, dynamic code generation, and comprehensive 
testing strategies.</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>yaml</keyword><keyword>configuration</keyword><keyword>geoprocessing</keyword><keyword>analysis</keyword><keyword>spatial analysis</keyword><keyword>toolbox</keyword><keyword>python</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><Consts><useLimit>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This toolbox is provided as-is for demonstration and educational purposes only.&lt;BR/&gt;Users may freely use, modify, and distribute this software subject to the&lt;BR/&gt;following conditions:&lt;BR/&gt;- Not intended for production use without thorough testing and validation&lt;BR/&gt;- No warranty expressed or implied for fitness for any particular purpose&lt;BR/&gt;- Users assume all responsibility for results and data quality&lt;BR/&gt;- Organizations should verify compliance with local data usage policies&lt;BR/&gt;- Consult with GIS administrators before deploying in enterprise environments&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</useLimit></Consts></resConst></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20260115</mdDateSt></metadata>